SUNMI SHIN

Antioch, TN 37013 | (937) 956-1738 | sunmishin9559@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sunmishin9559 | GitHub: github.com/sunmishin9559 | Website: sunmishin9559.github.io

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Developer with 4+ years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and debugging while staying focused on enhancing efficiency, stability, and scalability of system resources under strict deadlines. Creates a positive and efficient work environment with open communication in cross-functional teams to ensure quality of software application.

KEY SKILLS

Programming Java EE, C/C++/C#, Python, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.jS, React JS, HTML5/CSS, Bootstrap,

Tailwind CSS

Framework Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, NextJS

Databases Oracle SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Others Microsoft Office, Maven, JDBC, BI Publisher, Jaspersoft Studio, AWS, Windows Server 2012R2,

Apache, Tomcat, Jira, Azure DevOps, Git, SVN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rogers Group Inc | Application Developer | Nashville, TN

Jun 2023 - PRESENT

- Migrated and developed legacy Java application to Spring Boot
- Used Hibernate framework to map Oracle database and objects in the application.
- Designed and Developed jasper reports on spring java application by creating JRXML files in Jaspersoft Studio
- Managed work items or tasks in scrum methodology using Microsoft Azure DevOps

Hankook Tire America Corporation | Web Developer | Nashville, TN

Oct 2019 - Jun 2023

- Developed front-end for responsive web applications based on HTML/CSS along with JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap
- Developed back-end for web applications based on Spring MVC Framework along with Java, Maven, JDBC, MyBatis
- Developed RFC functions on SAP ERP with ABAP programming language and call RFC functions on web applications using sapico
- Developed a web application based on .NET Framework along with C# and Oracle DB
- Designed and created database and Data Manipulation with SQL Queries using Oracle SQL Developer
- Migrated on premise server for web applications to Bastion Server with Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Maintained Oracle Database for MES to resolve the issue and improve plant production process by understanding procedures written in PL/SQL
- Managed timeline and status for projects and inquiries using JIRA and Microsoft Teams Planner
- Hold cross-functional team meetings every month to share information and to achieve common goals
- Improved Web Security by implementing SSO (Single Sign-on), setting up password policy and account deactivation policy, checking IP address for admin accounts, and managing blacklist on AWS WAF
- Analyzed data stored on Oracle DB and SAP ERP using SQL Queries and Microsoft Excel to make the operation automatic and efficient, and increased the usage on the web system by 15%

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Alliance

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

Jun 2024

Wright State University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, magna cum laude

Dayton, OH

Wright State University

Dayton, OH

May 2014 - Dec 2018

Certificate, Cyber Security Analytics

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018